32 survivors, room for 12.
The Finest Hours is a action, drama, history film directed by Craig Gillespie.
The Coast Guard makes a daring rescue attempt off the coast of Cape Cod after a
pair of oil tankers are destroyed during a blizzard in 1952.
Bernie Webber, played by Chris Pine.
Ray Sybert, played by Casey Affleck.
Richard Livesey, played by Ben Foster.
Daniel Cluff, played by Eric Bana.
Miriam Webber, played by Holliday Grainger.
Wallace Quirey, played by John Ortiz.
The Finest Hours is a 2016 American action thriller film directed by
Craig Gillespie and produced by Walt Disney Pictures.
The screenplay, written by Eric Johnson, Scott Silver, and Paul Tamasy,
is based on The Finest Hours: The True Story of the U.S.
Coast Guard's Most Daring Sea Rescue by Michael J.
Tougias and Casey Sherman.
The film stars Chris Pine, Casey Affleck, Ben Foster, Holliday Grainger, John Ortiz, and Eric Bana, and chronicles the historic 1952 United
States Coast Guard rescue of the crew of SS Pendleton, after the ship split apart during a nor'easter off the New England coast.
The Finest Hours was released on January 29, 2016.
The film, which received mixed reviews from critics, was considered a box office flop for
only grossing $52 million worldwide on a $70–80 million production budget.
The film explores themes of coast guard, rescue mission,
based on true story, survival, storm at sea.
The tone is emotional and intense.